

# GAOPALELWE WILSON **MOLEKOA**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Engineering technologist with 6+ years experience in FMCG and the built environment. Transitioning into technology with a focus on back-end software development. Strong in project delivery, production goals, and cross-functional collaboration. Dedicated to excellence and ready to drive technological change.

Westfalia Fruto Moçambique - Chimoio,

• Equipment Performance Reporting: Monitored OEE

Daily Performance Updates: Reported daily metrics

• Data Management and Reporting: In collaboration

with the marketing team, developed spreadsheets

and used PowerBI for production insights and

reports, ensuring transparency and client

• Export Logistics Coordination: Organized export logistics and maintained production information for

Improved Day/Night Shift Operations: Enhanced

fruit packing efficiency by creating new

documentation, training staff to self-manage, and

delivering accurate reports promptly.

Westfalia Fruit Estates, Tzaneen, South Africa

Implemented Data-Driven Solutions: Used data

analysis tools to identify and resolve production

issues, boosting efficiency and reducing downtime.

improvement initiatives, enhancing quality, flow,

Optimized Operations: Led continuous

Project Management: Managed CAPEX budgets for

Cross-Functional Collaboration: Coordinated with

• Safety and Compliance Leadership: Enforced

Westfalia Fruit Estates, Tzaneen, South Africa

Achieved Aggressive Goals: Implemented

Boosted Productivity: Increased productivity by

Optimized Scheduling: Designed new production

Enhanced Collaboration: Cultivated partnerships

with engineering, marketing, and logistics teams.

Managed Shipments: Ensured on-time order

shipments by effectively managing production

15% through training programs and initiatives.

schedules, reducing labor and inventory loss.

Westfalia Fruit Estates, Tzaneen, South Africa

 Monitored Project Progress: Inspected sites to ensure adherence to design specifications, safety,

Managed Costs: Estimated project costs, prepared

Negotiated Contracts: Secured fair pricing and

quality service from suppliers and subcontractors.

Utilized CAD Software: Designed construction

• Ensured Quality Standards: Planned and

time and within-budget project completion.

Westfalia Fruit Estates, Tzaneen, South Africa

representations of civil structural designs.

liaison between clients and field personnel.

inspections and prepared take-offs for bids.

Assisted Design Representation: Created graphical

Surveyed Land: Measured and determined features

• Facilitated Client Communication: Acted as a

• Supported Bidding Process: Provided on-site

Monitored Construction Progress: Visited project

sites to consult with contractors and on-site

Civil Engineering Trainee Technician

of farmland for project planning.

implemented construction schedules, ensuring on-

plans and performed calculations using AutoCAD,

BOQs, and operated within budget guidelines.

performance and efficiency measures to meet

health and safety protocols, developing an ISO45001 compliant Health and Safety

departments to align production with customer

key projects, ensuring financial accountability and

and output with lean production techniques.

to growers and management, highlighting

and packing equipment performance,

**EXPERIENCE** 

Mozambique Lda.

Packhouse Shift Manager

improvement areas.

satisfaction.

compliance.

2020-2022

Production Manager

successful completion.

Management System.

**Assistant Production Manager** 

production targets.

activities.

Civil Engineering Technician

Revit, and PROKON.

2016-2017

and environmental standards.

2017-2018

2018-2020

needs, achieving business goals.

implementing improvements.

2024 Feb-June

#### **SKILLS SUMMARY**

- Languages: Python, SQL, HTML, XML, CSS, .json
- Frameworks: Django, Docker
- Tools: Github, SQLite, Excel, Powerpoint, Word, MS Dynamics, Sharepoint, Dropbox
- Platforms: Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text, Notepad++, DB Browser (SQLite)
- Soft Skills: Strong Stakeholder Management, Rapport Buidling, People Management, **Excelleng Communication**
- Technical Skills: Contracts management; Technical Report Writing, Development and Management of Health & Safety Management Systems (ISO45001 Standard), Application of Lean Manufacturing Principles/ Methodologies. Financial Management (Accrual Accounting; and CAPEX), Operations Management (Production Planning, Scheduling, Inventory Management & Quality Control)

#### PROJECTS/PORTFOLIO

#### **HyperionDev: Software Engineering Bootcamp**

Completed a rigorous software engineering bootcamp focusing on Python, Object Oriented Programming, and machine learning in just 6 months. Achieved a top 5 ranking in my cohort with a consistent 98% performance record. Follow my coding journey below and explore my transformative journey of software engineering.

View HyperionDev Portfolio

#### PayStree' App

Designed for young entrepreneurs in the catering and small restaurant industry, this back-end project builds robust data pipelines for take-out and delivery-centric businesses. I developed a bespoke relational database that captures and stores all business information, empowering owners to monitor performance through comprehensive dashboards. The solution focuses on three key areas: orders, stock control, and staff management. Take a look below..

View PayStree' App (Pending\_Build)

#### **Bank With Pvle\_TheEngineer**

By far my favorite and most challenging project, this endeavor involved building and deploying a banking app with finance management dashboards using Next.js 14. The app connects multiple bank accounts, displays real-time transactions, and enables money transfers between users on the platform. This project showcases my ability to integrate complex functionalities and deliver a seamless user experience in a financial application.

### View Bank With Pvle\_TheEngineer (pending)

### **CVs With Pvle\_TheEngineer**

This project was an exercise in learning Laravel to master PHP. Using my new skills, I created a free and simple CV (resume) builder aimed at job seekers, ensuring it is over 80% ATS-proof. This project demonstrates my ability to develop practical, userfriendly web applications with Laravel.

View CVs With Pvle\_TheEngineer(Pending)

### **EDUCATION**

2019 - 2021

**B-Tech Engineering Civil: Construction** Management

Tshwane University of Technology, Pretoria, South Africa

2018 - 2019

Post-Graduate Certificate - Executive Development

University of Stellenbosch, Stellenbosch, South Africa

2014 - 2017

N Dip Engineering Civil

Tshwane University of Technology, Pretoria, South Africa

# **AWARDS**

engineers.

2024

Hyperion Development: Software Engineering Bootcamp

(Pending)

2014

Tshwane University of Technology: N Dip **Engineering Civil** 

Civil Engineering: S1 Distinction Award

## **INTERESTS**

 $\square$ 亞 Music Technology & Engineering Travel

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

2024

HyperionDev: Software Engineering Bootcamp HyperionDev.

Teacher Record: TEFL Certificate 120-hrs

2023

TeacherRecord

2020

BRCGS: Global Standard for Food Safety Issue 8: Sites Training

**BRCGS** 

2019

Hazard Analysis & Critical Control Points: Intermediate Level

2019

Occupational Health & Safety Act No 85 of 1993 & **Regulations for Managers** 

ABE Bosman Attorneys

### **CONTACT DETAILS**

Pretoria, South Africa, 0157

+27 65 850 6336

@ gwmolekoa@gmail.com

## **SOCIALS**

₩ /GWMolekoa

ൂ്ത gaopalelwe-wilson-molekoa

O pvle\_m

灯 pvle\_m